ZEN JUEN LAU

• https://zen-juen.github.io

∠ lauzenjuen@gmail.com

Curriculum Vitae

EDUCATION

Master of Clinical Neuropsychology (MClinNeuro)

2022 - Present

Macquarie University

Master of Arts, Psychology, First Class Honours

2015 - 2019

University of Edinburgh

SUMMARY

My research interests lie in higher-order cognitive processes and how they are affected by disruptions to neural circuitry in neurological disorders. I am also particularly interested in ideas of brain complexity and entropy and hope to use computational modelling to improve diagnostic and psychological outcomes for neuropsychiatric disorders. On the side, I help to develop open-source software for improving the ease and accessibility of research tools for psychology and neuroscience researchers.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

2019 - Present

Nanyang Technological University (NTU), Clinical Brain Lab, Singapore

<u>Advisors</u>: Professor S. H. Annabel Chen, Dr. Dominique Makowski Project: Investigating the Neurophysiological Correlates of Deception

Honor's Thesis

2018 - 2019

University of Edinburgh, UK

Advisor: Professor Robert Logie

Thesis: Flashbulb Memories of Public and Private Events: Detailed but Not Special

Group Research Project

2017 - 2018

University of Edinburgh, UK

Advisor: Dr. Alexa Morcom

Project: Associative False Recognition without Prior Recall in Young and Old populations

CLINICAL EXPERIENCE

Mental Health Care Support Worker

SLV.Global Mental Health Placement

June - July 2018

Psychology Intern

Drug Rehabilitation Centre, Singapore Prison Service

May - August 2017

PUBLICATIONS

*joint-first authorship

Lau*, Z. J., Pham*, T., Chen, S. A., & Makowski, D. (under review). Brain Entropy, Fractal Dimensions and Predictability: A Review of Complexity Measures for EEG in Healthy and Neuropsychiatric Populations. PsyArXiv.

Pham, T., Lau, Z. J., Chen, S. A., & Makowski, D. (under review). Unveiling the Structure of Heart Rate Variability (HRV) Indices: A Data-driven Meta-clustering Approach. PsyArXiv.

Makowski, D., Lau, Z. J., Pham, T., Chen, S. A. (under review). Psychological Determinants of the Susceptibility to Fake News amidst the COVID-19 Pandemic.

Makowski, D., Lau, Z. J., Pham, T., Boyce, P., S H Chen, A. Pyllusion: A Parametric Framework to Generate Visual Illusions using Python. (2021). Perception, 50(11), 950-965.

Pham, T., Lau, Z. J., Chen, S. A., Makowski, D. Heart Rate Variability in Psychology: A Review of HRV Indices and an Analysis Tutorial. Sensors 2021, 21, 3998.

Makowski, D., Pham, T., Lau, Z. J., Raine, A., & Chen, S. A. (2021). The structure of deception: Validation of the lying profile questionnaire. Current Psychology, 1-16.

Makowski, D., Pham, T., Lau, Z. J., Brammer, J. C., Lespinasse, F., Pham, H., Schölzel, C., & Chen, S. A. (2021). NeuroKit2: A Python toolbox for neurophysiological signal processing. Behavior Research Methods, 1-8.%

Pansuwan*, T., Breuer*, F., Gazder*, T., Lau*, Z. J., Cueva, S., Swanson, L., ... Morcom, A. (2020). Evidence for age-invariance of associative false recognition. Memory, 28(2), 172-186.

TALKS

Lau, Z. J. (2019). Are Flashbulb Memories Different from Ordinary Autobiographical Memories? British Psychological Society (BPS) Undergraduate Conference 2019, Glasgow, United Kingdom.

POSTERS

Lau, Z. J., Pham, T., Boyce, W. P., Chen, S. A., & Makowski, D. (2021). A Parametric Framework to Generate Visual Illusions using Python. 43rd European Conference on Visual Perception, 22-27 Aug. Online.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

Clinical Brain Lab, Nanyang Technological University

Introduction to R for Psychological Science

September 2019

Introduction to GitHub Workshop

June 2020

Peer Assisted Learning (PALS) Tutor

Psychology Department, University of Edinburgh

September 2018 - May 2019

Lead class discussions and organize academic-based resources for pre-honours psychology students to consolidate learning. Conduct drop-in sessions to discuss course material, assignments and tips for exam preparation. Sessions designed for students in PSYL08001, PPLS08001, PSYL08011, PSYL08012.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS AND SERVICE

Graduate Member, British Psychological Society	2021
Reviewer, Journal of Open Source Software	2021 - Present

SPECIALIZED SKILLS

IRB Applications, Progress reports, Publications, **Project Management**

Conference posters, Financial budgeting

Participants Recruitment, Training student RAs

Data Collection Methods Qualtrics, Behavioural, EEG, fMRI

Electrocardiogram (ECG), Electrodermal activity (EDA),

Electromyography (EMG), Respiration, Electroocoulogram (EOG) R, Python, E-prime®, PsychoPy, jsPsych, Git, LaTeX, AcqKnowledge

Languages English (Native), Mandarin Chinese (Native), Hokkien (Basic)

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

Research Stack

fMRI Preprocessing and Analysis Workshop

November 2021

3-day workshop organized by Dr Joyce Wu Chiao-Yi (Clinical Brain Lab, NTU) on Matlab and SPM12 for fMRI analysis

Human Brain Mapping Educational Courses

June 2021

Organization for Human Brain Mapping (OHBM) 2021

First Aid Courses June 2021

Certified in Psychological First Aid, Pandemic First Aid, and First Aid Kit mastery for support during emergencies and their aftermaths in a 22-hour long course organized by Singapore First Aid Training Centre

Creating Experiments in PsychoPy

October 2020

Intensive training in research methods and programming at a postgraduate level by Open Science Tools Ltd

CITI Certification August 2019

Collaborative Institutional Training Initiative for Ethics and Scientific Integrity in Research

ERIC Certification August 2019

Epigeum Research Integrity Course - Social and Behavioural Sciences Track

HONORS AND AWARDS

Healthcare Graduate Studies Award

Full-ride postgraduate scholarship offered by Ministry of Health Holdings, Singapore to read Clinical Psychology (Neuropsychology) in Australia 2021

Edinburgh Award

Recognition of contribution as Psychology Peer Assisted Learning leader

2019

Principal's Go Abroad Fund

£350 grant awarded by University of Edinburgh to fund SLV.GLobal Mental Health Placement

2018

Edusave Award for Achievement, Good Leadership and Service (EAGLES)

Awarded by Ministry of Education (MOE) (Singapore) for student leadership qualities and excellence in service to community and schools

SERVICES AND LEADERSHIP

Student Ambassador, SLV.Global

Organize and host information sessions on SLV.Global placements at Universities, communicate with different stakeholders, network with students to raise awareness of mental health needs in developing countries.

Recruitment Committee, Psychology Peer Assisted Learning

Recruitment of student leaders to enrol as psychology student academic facilitators.

2019

Editor, Edinburgh University Psychology Magazine

Also author of Behind Prison Walls: The Psychology of Drug Crime in Issue Psychology in the World. See different issues & here.

Publicity Director, Edinburgh University Singapore Society (EUSS)

Oversee welfare of its members through organizing gatherings, large-scale events, socials, and career information sessions. Manage social media platforms, designing, and publicity strategies. 2016 - 2017

Intern, Beyond Social Services (Singapore)

Work with organizations to provide employment opportunities for low-income individuals, produce financial assistance reports and social reports on socio-economic profiles of clients.

Intern, Psychology Department, AMKFSC Community Services (Singapore)

Plan and deliver conflict management workshops for children with anger management difficulties, practice handson Motivational Interviewing and Cognitive Behavioural Therapy. 2015